Benjamin Pearce

25 Welbeck Rise, Harpenden, Hertfordshire, AL5 1RT

Email: ben.pearce25@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://benp99.github.io/portfolio/

Mobile: 07443479846

Personal Summary

I am a passionate developer which my specialities being games and website development. One of my biggest achievements was the completion of my three year course at the University of Hertfordshire, the course being BSc (Hons) Computer Science (Software Engineering) which I completed with a 1st. As this course had a specialisation in software engineering I learnt a lot about the principles and practices which I still use to this day.

As a highly motivated and experienced developer, both in professional work environments and personal projects, I have gained experience with games and website development proven by the projects shown in my portfolio and the professional work experience I have gained. Because of this experience I have a proven ability to work within teams of developers to produce quality solutions, but also the ability to learn and adapt in new work environments.

Education and Qualifications:

University of Hertfordshire: 2017-2021

Course: BSc (Hons) Computer Science (Software Engineering) First Class

Year 1: Human Dimensions of Computing, Programming, Models and Methods in Computing, and Platforms for Computing.

Year 2: Contemporary Issues, Database Concepts, Computer Science Development Exercise, Algorithms and Data Structures, Artificial Intelligence, Operating Systems and Networks, The C Family.

Year 3: Project Planning, Final Project, Mobile Computing, Computer Systems Security, Object Orientated Programming, Programming Paradigms, Software Engineering Practice.

Bedford College: 2015-2017

Course: BTEC Level 3 Diploma in IT (2 Years) Achieved a Double Grade Distinction* Distinction*

Year 1: Communication and Employability Skills for IT, Computer Systems, Computer Networks, IT Systems Troubleshooting and Repair, Website Production, Event Driven Programming

Year 2: Clientside Customisation of Web Pages, Spreadsheet Modelling, Communications Technologies, Managing Networks, Information Systems, IT Technical Support

Sir John Lawes: 2010-2015 GCSE

Maths, English Literature, English Language, Science, Additional Science, ICT, History, Art & Design, German, *Short Course* RE

Work Experience:

Iken – Web Developer: July 2021 – Present

I am part of the development team at Iken who work on the Iken product, which is used by their clients, in an Agile SCRUM environment; this could include responsibilities from fixing bugs to adding new features to the product. Many technologies are used, such as: Angular JS, Typescript, C#, ASP.Net, HTML, CSS, SASS, GIT, Visual Studio, and Azure DevOps. In this role my responsibilities are: to fix bugs raised, implement new features, and to review the pull requests of work done by other developers before they get merged to the master branch and get used in the next release.

eArcu – Front End Developer: August 2019 – July 2020

As part of my University course I took part in a work placement for 1 year, which took place between my second and third year of University. I worked within a team of front end web developers that developed recruitment sites for clients, and within the team we also had a QA rotation which meant we also tested are own work in the team before it was approved. This means that not only did this role five me experience as a developer, but also as a tester as when it my turn in the QA rotation I would go through the completed tickets of any changes made and do the final tests before I approved the tickets or sent them back with notes on the changes needed.

Lumesse Ltd – Infrastructure Engineer: February 2017

As part of my College Work Experience I spent a week at Lumesse as an Infrastructure Engineer. My responsibilities were to manage and take apart old servers in the company's server room as the unused RAM was needed for other devices. Another of my responsibilities was to delete old Logical Drives. I enjoyed the experience and learnt about the inner workings of servers used in networking.

Barclays Bank – Customer Service: February 2016

At the college's suggestion I did another work experience placement, this placement was as Customer Service in Barclays Bank. This role contained a lot of experience with customer facing responsibilities within the bank, such as showing people how to use the ATMs. The experience gained from this role was very interesting and helped enhance my skills with talking and interacting with clients that will help me as I continue to pursue a career in development as I will need these skills to interact with future clients.

Lumesse Ltd – Front End Developer: June 2014

This was my School Work Experience during my time at Sir John Lawes in which I worked with the Front End Development team to help build recruitment websites for live clients. These websites

would compromise of a backend with a SQL database and a public facing front end which the team I worked in was responsible for, and the front end of these websites would be hosted from a server located in one of the company's databases once the site was ready to go live. This placement was my introduction to Website Development and was where I first learned HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Awards:

Nominated for BCS Innovation Award for BSc Final Project

School Graduation Prize for achieving an exceptionally high result (University of Hertfordshire)

Volunteer Work:

St Albans Library – IT Champion: November 2016 – June 2017

I volunteered at St Albans Library as an IT Champion. As an IT Champion I helped with IT related problems around the library, more specifically I dealt with queries for users who would come to use the library computers. These queries could range from simple queries to more complex queries. An example of a simple query could be sending an email, and an example of a more complex query could be that the computer would not turn on or the user could not login to the computers with their given accounts.

Harpenden Warhammer and Tabletop Games – Club Supervisor: May 2019 – Current

I currently volunteer as a club supervisor at Harpenden Warhammer and Tabletop Games in which I help organise and plan events that take place at the club, and I also help to manage these events as they take place. This also means that I sort out any disagreements that happen during games at the club and act as a referee for games played in the club to make sure everyone follows the rules while still having fun.

Skills Summary:

- Experience with Unity for personal projects, both for 2D and 3D games. See Portfolio for details on my completed projects.
- As I use Unity, I have a lot of experience using C#.
- I also use Visual Studio IDE to write the scripts I use in my Unity projects.
- Have a small amount of experience in Unreal Engine; however I prefer to use Unity for personal projects.
- The first game engine I used was Game Maker Studio in secondary school when I started learning to program.
- I have researched a considerable amount about Game Design and Games Development for my Final Project for University, this project can be found on my Portfolio.
- I learnt about C and C++ in one of my University modules.
- I also have a good amount of experience in Java and Python.
- With my experience in website development I have learnt the following languages:
 - o HTML

- CSS and SASS
- JavaScript and Typescript
- o Professional Angular JS experience
- o Some experience with jQuery
- o PHP
- Professional SQL experience
- I have experience using Bootstrap to make websites responsive among a wide range of different screen sizes.
- Experience in GitHub and GitBash.
- Small amount of experience with Ruby and Scala, which I learnt at University.
- During my time at University I learnt about Object Orientated Programming and the Principles of Software Engineering. I have put into practice what I learnt through work experience and personal projects.
- Proficient with Microsoft Office programs, for example: Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, and Publisher.
- I have a good work ethic and have experience working in teams of other developers.

Hobbies and Interests:

- I am learning Japanese.
- I like to make and produce my own music using the Digital Audio Workstation FL Studio.
- I have played Squash and received 3 trophies and a variety of Silver and Bronze medals.
- I have studied a form of Martial Arts called Ju Jitsu, and I achieved up to purple belt.
- In my spare time I like to design and develop game projects, details of my past projects are shown on my Portfolio.
- I enjoy playing a variety of video games and take inspiration from these games when designing and developing my own game projects.

References:

Mr. Sam Liddy: Davenport House, Bowers Way, Harpenden, AL5 4HX.

Email: sam.liddy@earcu.com

Miss. Joanne Smith: St Albans Central library, The Maltings, St Albans AL1 3JQ.

Email: <u>Joanne.Smith1@hertfordshire.gov.uk</u>